Register of the Sir Karl Raimund Popper Papers, 1928-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS I, 1928-1986
  - Conjectures and Refutations, 1962
    - English version
      - First edition, 1962
        - Typescript and holograph
          - Chapter 3 (Folder 8)
          - Chapter 4 (Folder 9)
          - Chapter 5 (Folder 10)
          - Chapter 6 (Folder 11)
          - Chapter 7. (Box 61, Folder 1)
            Includes German version
          - Chapter 8 (Folder 2)
          - Chapter 9 (Folder 3)
          - Chapter 10 (Folder 4-5)
          - Chapter 11 (Folder 6)
          - Chapters, 12-13 (Folder 7)
          - Chapter 14 (Folder 8)
          - Chapter 15 (Folder 9)
          - Chapter 16 (Folder 10)
          - Chapter 17 (Folder 11)
          - Chapter 18 (Folder 12)
          - Chapter 19 (Folder 13)
          - Chapter 20 (Folder 14)
          - Appendices (Folder 15)
          - Index of names (Folder 16)
          - Index of subjects (Box 62, Folder 1)
        - Proofs (Folder 2-4)
        - Proofs (Box 63, Folder 1)
        - Reviews (Folder 2)
      - Reprint of first edition, 1964
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Indices. Typescript (Folder 4-5)
        - Reviews (Folder 6)
      - Second edition, 1965
        - Typescript and holograph
          - General (Folder 7-8)
          - Indices (Folder 9)
        - Proofs (Folder 10)
        - Reviews (Folder 11)
      - Third edition, 1969
        - Typescript and holograph. General. (Box 64, Folder 1-3)
        - Proofs (Folder 4-7)
        - Proofs (Box 65, Folder 1)
        - Reviews (Folder 2)
      - Seventh impression, 1978. Extract entitled "Science: Conjectures and Refutations," published in The Search for the Human Sciences, Printed copy, 1980. (Box 459, Folder 9)
    - Spanish version, Second edition, 1983. Correspondence, 1983, 1967. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Italian version, Reviews, 1972. (Folder 4)
    - German version (not published)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1969
        - Kiesewetter, R., 1967-1969 (Folder 5)
        - Oppacher, Franz, 1967-1968 (Folder 6)
        - Schleichert, Hubert, 1967 (Folder 7)
        - Walentik, Leonhard, 1967 (Folder 8)
        - Weingartner, Paul, 1967 (Folder 9)
      - Typescript and holograph
        - General. (Folder 10-13)
          Includes correspondence, 1974, and fragments translated by Lisbeth Gombrich
        - Introduction (translation by Gretl Albert). (Folder 14-17)
          Includes translation of other chapters and correspondence with Grete Albert, 1979
        - Introduction (Box 66, Folder 1-4)
        - Chapter 1. (Folder 5-7)
          Includes translation by R. Kiesewetter
        - Chapter 2 (Box 67, Folder 1-3)
        - Chapter 3 (Folder 4-6)
        - Chapter 4 (translation by Hermann Fischer). (Folder 7-8)
          Includes correspondence with Hermann Fischer, 1970
        - Chapter 5 (Folder 9-11)
        - Chapter 6 (Folder 12)
        - Chapter 7 (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
        - Chapter 8 (Folder 3)
        - Chapter 9 (Folder 4)
        - Chapter 10 (Folder 5)
        - Chapter 11 (Folder 6)
        - Chapter 12 (Folder 7)
        - Chapter 13 (Folder 8)
        - Chapter 14 (Folder 9)
        - Chapter 15 (Folder 10)
        - Chapter 16 (Folder 11)
        - Chapter 17 (Folder 12)
        - Chapter 18 (Folder 13)
        - Chapter 19 (Folder 14)
        - Chapter 20 (Box 69, Folder 1)
        - Addenda (Folder 2)
    - French version, 1985
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Folder 3)
      - Printed copy (Folder 4)
    - Japanese version, Correspondence
      - Ichii, Saburo, 1967-1968 (Folder 5)
      - Nakamura, Junichi, 1967-1975 (Folder 6)
  - "Historical Explanation: An Interview," Cambridge Opinion, Holograph, typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, 1962. (Folder 7)
  - "Julius Kraft, 1898-1960," Ratio, 1962
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Holograph (Folder 9)
    - Typescript (Folder 10)
    - Printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "Knowledge and Society," Speech, Berkeley, California. Holograph and typescript, 1962. (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - "A New Prediction Paradox," British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, Typescript, 1962. (Folder 2)
  - "On Carnap's Version of Laplace's Rule of Succession," Mind, 1962. Holograph and typescript. (Folder 3)
    Includes Richard C. Jeffrey's reply and letter of 1962 February 14.See also "The Mysteries of Udolpho: A Reply to Professors Jeffrey and Bar-Hillel," 1967 January
  - "Uber Geschichtsschreibung und uber den Sinn der Geschichte," Geist und Gesicht der Gegenwart, 1962 (revised version of Open Society and Its Enemies, chapter 25). Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "The Erewhonians and the Open Society," Speech, San Francisco State College, San Francisco, California, 1962 March 14.
    - English version
      - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 5)
      - Typescript and holograph (Folder 6)
      - Printed copy (Folder 7)
    - German version. Typescript and correspondence, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Contribution to the discussion sessions following the three lectures given by Bertrand de Jouvenel on the art of conjecture, Geneva, Switzerland, (organized by the Congress for Cultural Freedom and by the Graduate Institute of International Studies), 1962 June 25-28
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Notes (Folder 11)
  - "On the Status and the Methods of Science," Radio broadcast, British Broadcasting Corporation, London, England, 1963
    - Early version
      - Holograph (Folder 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 13)
    - Later version. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - "Science: Problems and How to Solve Them," Speech, MENSA, London, England. Typescript., 1963. (Folder 15)
    Includes correspondence, 1963
  - "The Open Society," Speech, Bloomington, Indiana, 1963 February 14.
    - Typescript (Folder 16)
    - Revised version, "The Open Society and the Democratic State," Indian Institute of Public Administration, Delhi, India, 1963 August
      - Typescript and holograph (Folder 17)
      - Typescript (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Review (Folder 2)
    - Revised version, San Francisco, California, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Models, Instruments and Truth: The Rationality Principle in the Sciences," Speech, Department of Economics, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Bergson, Abram and Conrad, Alfred H., 1963 February 26.
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Typescript and holograph (Folder 5-10)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
    - Abstract entitled "Rationality and the Status of the Rationality Principle," in Les Fondements philosophiques des systemes economiques: Textes de Jacques Rueff et essais rediges en son honneur, 23 aout 1966, 1967
      - English version, 1966.
        Includes correspondence, 1966
        - Holograph (Folder 5-6)
        - Typescript (Folder 7-9)
        - Correspondence (Folder 10)
      - French version, Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 11)
      - Spanish version, Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 12)
  - "The Problem of Scientific Knowledge" Two speeches, Princeton University, New Jersey, 1963 February 28.
    - Part I. Typescript and holograph (Folder 13)
    - Part II. Typescript (Folder 14)
    - Correspondence (Folder 15)
    - Clipping (Folder 16)
  - "Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities," Speech, Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1963 April 17.
    - English version, 1963
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Folder 18-19)
      - Holograph (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 2-10)
      - Proofs (Folder 11)
      - Printed copy (Folder 12)
    - Italian version, Printed copy, 1966. (Folder 13)
  - "Objectivity and Subjectivity in Scientific Method," Speech, Queens College. Typescript and holograph outline, 1963 April 19. (Folder 14)
  - "Problems of Scientific Knowledge," Speech, University of Illinois, Chicago, 1963 April 25.
    - Typescript (Folder 15)
    - Japanese translation, Printed copy, 1963. (Box 459, Folder 10)
  - "Creative and Non-Creative Definitions in the Calculus of Probability," Synth'se, 1963 June
    - Early versions. Holograph and typescript
      - "Axioms and Definitions of the Probability Calculus" (Box 73, Folder 16)
      - "Productive and Non-Productive Formal Definitions in the Calculus of Probability" (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Final version
      - Holograph and typescript. (Folder 2)
        Includes correspondence, 1962-1963
      - Proofs (Folder 3)
      - Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Kirk on Heraclitus, and on Fire as the Cause of Balance," Mind, Reply to G. S. Kirk, "Back to the Pre-Socratics." Printed copy, 1963 July. (Folder 5)
  - "Research in Science: Problems, and How to Solve Them," Speech, Institute of Advanced Studies, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia. Typescript and holograph, 1963 July 22. (Folder 6-8)
  - "The Improbability of Explanatory Hypotheses,", 1964
    - General. Notes and research material (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence
      - Curnow, R. N., 1964. (Folder 10)
        Includes fragments of typescript
      - Freed, Julius, 1964 (Folder 11)
      - Lakatos, Imre, 1964. (Folder 12)
        Includes correspondence with Paul Bernays, Arend Heyting, Stephen C. Kleene, D. W. MacKinnon, Hao Wang
      - Silvey, S. D., 1964 (Folder 13)
    - Typescript and holograph. (Folder 14-15)
      Includes correspondence, 1964
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 75, Folder 1-2)
  - Untitled seminars (six), Vienna, Austria, Holograph, 1964 June. (Folder 3)
  - Speech relating to relativity theory, Typescript, 1964 August 4. (Folder 4)
  - "Normal Science and Its Dangers," Paper, International Colloquium in the Philosophy of Science, London, England, 1965.
    - General. (Folder 5)
      Includes Karl Popper's contribution to the Kuhn-Watkins discussion, and Imre Lakatos, "Demarcation Criterion and Scientific Research Programmes"
    - English version
      - Holograph (Folder 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 7-8)
      - Printed copy with corrections (Folder 9)
    - German version. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "On Problems and How to Understand Them," Speech, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1965 April. (Folder 11)
  - "Of Clouds and Clocks: An Approach to the Problem of Rationality and the Freedom of Man," The Arthur Holly Compton Memorial Lecture, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, 1965 April 21.
    - General. (Box 76, Folder 1)
      Includes outlines and fragments
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1965-1969 (Folder 2)
      - Karlson, Marjorie, 1965 (Folder 3)
      - Litvag, Irving, 1965 (Folder 4)
      - Malmquist, Carl P., 1968 (Folder 5)
      - McCormick, M. L., 1967 (Folder 6)
      - O'Brian, Frank, 1965-1968 (Folder 7)
      - Pake, George E., 1964-1965 (Folder 8)
      - Papanek, Helene, 1966 (Folder 9)
      - Rudner, Richard S., 1965-1966 (Folder 10)
      - Spiegelberg, Herbert, 1965 (Folder 11)
      - Standen, Gray, 1965-1968 (Folder 12)
      - Zollschan, George K., 1968 (Folder 13)
    - Holograph (Folder 14-15)
    - Typescript
      - Early versions (Folder 16-17)
      - Early versions (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Later versions (Folder 2-13)
    - Proofs (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Printed copy (Folder 2)
    - Reviews (Folder 3)
  - "The Myth of the Framework," Seminar, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota., 1965 April 23.
    Includes speech "On Problems and How to Understand Them" and discussion
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
    - Revised version, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, 1965 April 26
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Folder 5)
      - Typescript and holograph (Folder 6)
    - Revised version, Brandeis University, Waltham, Massachusetts, Typescript and notes, 1969 November 19. (Folder 7-8)
    - Revised version, Dunedin, New Zealand, Typescript, 1973. (Folder 9)
      - English version
        - General. (Folder 10)
          Includes correspondence, 1973
        - Typescript and holograph (Box 79, Folder 1-7)
        - Proofs (Folder 8)
        - Printed copy, 1976 (Folder 9)
      - German version. Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "Rationality and the Search for Invariants," Speech, International Colloquium on the Philosophy of Science, Bedford College, London, England., 1965 July 11.
    Includes material relating to the colloquium's organization
    - General. (Box 80, Folder 1-2)
      Includes papers by Oliver E. Ford, Stephan Korner, and L. Pearce Williams, and transcripts of discussion sessions
    - Correspondence.
      - Church, Alonzo, 1964 (Folder 3)
      - Findlay, Allan F., 1967 (Folder 4)
      - Freudenthal, H., 1964 (Folder 5)
      - Godel, Kurt, 1964 (Folder 6)
      - Henkin, Leon, 1964 (Folder 7)
      - Heyting, Arend, 1964 (Folder 8)
      - Kuhn, Thomas S., 1964. (Folder 9)
        Includes Thomas S. Kuhn, "Logic of Discovery or Psychology of Research: A Gestalt Switch?"
      - Quine, Willard Van Orman, 1964 (Folder 10)
      - Robinson, Abraham, 1964 (Folder 11)
    - Notes. Typescript and holograph (Folder 12)
    - Holograph (Folder 13)
    - Typescript (Folder 14-20)
    - Typescript (Box 81, Folder 1-12)
  - Lecture, Symposium of Inductive Logic, Bedford College, London, England, 1965 July 17.
    - General. (Folder 13)
    - Typescript and holograph (Folder 14)
    - Papers read by others (Folder 15)
      - Bunge, Mario, "Induction: A Motely Assembly." Typescript
      - Carnap, Rudolf, "Inductive Logic and Inductive Intuitions." Typescript
      - Hilpinen, Risto, "On Epistemic Utility: Comments on Dr. Vetter's Paper." Typescript
      - Hintikka, Jaakko, "Conditionalization and Information: Two Marginal Comments on Carnap's Paper." Typescript
      - Lejewski, Czeslaw, "Quantification and Ontological Commitment." Typescript
      - Watkins, John W. N., "Hume, Carnap and Popper," and "Decision and Belief." Typescripts
    - Transcript of discussion between Karl Popper, Rudolf Carnap, William C. Kneale, Paul Bernays, and Yehoshua Bar-Hillel. Typescript and proofs (Folder 16)
  - "Time's Arrow and Entropy," Nature, 1965 July 17
    - General (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Folder 2)
    - Holograph (Folder 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 4)
    - Proofs (Folder 5)
  - "Why Zeno was Right," Speech. Typescript and holograph, 1965 September. (Folder 6)
  - "Otto Neurath: Memories and Impressions," Typescript, 1966? (Folder 7)
  - Foreword to L. M. Loring, Two Kinds of Values, Typescript and holograph, 1966. (Folder 8)
  - "A Note on the Theory of the Cold War," Typescript, 1966. (Folder 9)
  - "A Theorem on Truth Content," in Paul K. Feyerabend and Grover Maxwell, ed., Mind, Matter, and Method: Essays in Philosophy of Science in Honor of Herbert Feigl, 1966
    - Correspondence
      - Maxwell, Grover, 1963-1965. (Folder 10)
        Includes correpondence with William W. Bartley, III, Imre Lakatos, and Jacob Bruno Bronowski
      - Shechtman, Joseph, 1965 (Folder 11)
    - Holograph (Folder 12)
    - Typescript (Folder 13)
    - Proofs for illustrations (Folder 14)
    - Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "A Note on the Difference Between the Lorentz-Fitzgerald Contraction and the Einstein Contraction," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, Typescript and holograph., 1966 February. (Folder 16)
    Includes correspondence, 1965
  - "The Influence of Einstein on my View of Science," Radio broadcast, British Broadcasting Corporation, London, England. Typescript, 1966 February 23. (Folder 17)
  - Lecture series, University of Denver, Denver, Colorado, Typescript and holograph outlines and notes. See also "A Realist View of Logic, Physics and History," 1966 May, 1966 March 30-June 1.
    - General (Folder 18)
    - Lecture no. Relates to historical knowledge, 1, March 30. (Folder 19)
    - Lecture no. Relates to theory of knowledge and art, 2, April 6. (Folder 20)
    - Lecture no. Relates to historicism, 3, n.d. (Folder 21)
    - Lecture no. Relates to relativism, 4, n.d. (Folder 22)
    - Lecture no. Relates to relativism, 5, May 5. (Folder 23)
    - Lecture no. Relates to historicism, 6, May 11. (Folder 24)
    - Lecture no. Relates to the Cold War, 8, May 25. (Folder 25)
    - Lecture no. Relates to philosophy of history, 9, June 1. (Folder 26)
  - "A Comment on Miller's New Paradox of Information," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, Typescript and holograph. See also "The Mysteries of Udolpho: A Reply to Professors Jeffrey and Bar-Hillel," 1967 January, 1966 May. (Folder 27)
  - "A Realist View of Logic, Physics and History," Paper, International Colloquium on Logic, Physics and History, University of Denver, Denver, Colorado., 1966 May.
    Includes material relating to the conference and to Karl Popper's tenure as visiting professor
    - General. (Folder 28)
      Includes papers by Jean-Pierre Vigier, Jaakko Hintikka, and Andre Mercier, and Karl Popper's remarks upon these
    - Correspondence
      - Matzka, John, 1968 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Miller, David W., 1966-1967 (Folder 2)
      - Yourgrau, Wolfgang, 1966-1969. (Folder 3)
        Includes corrections to manuscript
    - Holograph. (Folder 4)
      Includes "Remarks on Ranki's Paper"
    - Typescript (Folder 5-7)
    - Printed copy (Folder 8-10)
  - "Education versus Common Sense," Commencement speech, University of Denver, Denver, Colorado, 1966 June 10.
    - General (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Folder 2)
    - Typescript (Folder 3)
  - "The Paradox of Zero Information," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1966 August
    - Correspondence, 1966. (Folder 4)
      Includes corrected typescript and corrected proofs
    - Holograph (Folder 5)
    - Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Comment on Carnap's 'Inductive Logic and Inductive Intuitions,'" The Problem of Inductive Logic, Typescript, 1967? (Folder 7)
  - "Three Idols of Empiricism: Precision - Definition - The Senses and their Data," Speech, La Jolla, California. Typescript and notes, 1967? (Folder 8-12)
  - Contribution to Imre Lakatos memorial volume, Notes., 1967. (Folder 13)
    Includes Imre Lakatos, "A Renaissance of Empiricism in the Recent Philosophy of Mathematics"
  - "The Cosmological Origins of Euclidean Geometry," in Imre Lakatos, ed., Problems in the Philosophy of Mathematics, Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 14)
  - "Einstein: An Interview," in Gerald J. Whitrow, ed., Einstein: The Man and His Achievement, Printed copy of an excerpt, 1967. (Folder 15)
  - "Quantum Mechanics without 'The Observer,'" in Mario Bunge, ed., Quantum Theory and Reality (volume two of Studies in the Foundations, Methodology, and Philosophy of Science ), 1967
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 16-17)
      - Unidentified, 1967 (Folder 18)
      - Bohm, David J., 1967. (Folder 19)
        Includes typescript with corrections
      - Musgrave, Alan, 1967 (Folder 20)
      - Miller, David W., 1967 (Folder 21)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 85, Folder 1-8)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 86, Folder 1-8)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 87, Folder 1-11)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 88, Folder 1-12)
    - Proofs (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
    - Printed copy (Folder 3)
  - "The Mysteries of Udolpho: A Reply to Professors Jeffrey and Bar-Hillel," Mind, See also "On Carnap's Version of Laplace's Rule of Succession," 1962, and "A Comment on Miller's New Paradox of Information," 1966 May, 1967 January.
    - Correspondence with Gilbert Ryle, 1965. (Folder 4)
      Includes corrected proofs
    - Typescript and holograph. (Folder 5-7)
      Includes early draft entitled "Demonstrable Irrelevance: A Reply to Professor Richard C. Jeffrey"
    - Typescript and holograph (Folder 8-9)
    - Typescript and holograph (Box 90, Folder 1-2)
    - Mimeographed copy intended to be published in an essay volume entitled "Six Contributions to the Theory of Induction." (Folder 3)
      Includes contributions by Yehoshua Bar-Hillel, Richard C. Jeffrey, and David W. Miller
  - "Time's Arrow and Feeding on Negentropy," Nature, Reply to Wolfgang Buchel, 1967 January 21.
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966. (Folder 4)
      Includes Wolfgang Buchel, "On Entropy and Information in the Universe"
    - Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Structural Information and the Arrow of Time," Nature, Reply to H. W. Woolhouse. Printed copy, 1967 April 15. (Folder 7)
  - "Epistemology without a Knowing Subject," Speech, Third International Congress for Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, Amsterdam, Holland, 1967 August 25.
    - First version
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Correspondence
        - Anstadt, Dr., 1971 (Folder 9)
        - Elders, Fons, 1971 (Folder 10)
        - Kampen, Miss van, 1971 (Folder 11)
        - Nederlandse Omroep Stichting, 1971 (Folder 12)
        - North Holland Publishing Company, 1968 (Folder 13)
        - Rijntjes, G. J. P., 1971 (Folder 14)
        - Rootselaar, B. van, 1967 (Folder 15)
      - Notes (Folder 16)
      - Holograph (Folder 17-19)
      - Typescript (Box 91, Folder 1-15)
      - Typescript (Box 92, Folder 1-7)
      - Proofs (Folder 8)
      - Printed copy with corrections (Folder 9)
    - Second version, Proofs and printed copies of 1967 version with corrections, 1972. (Box 93, Folder 1-4)
    - Third version, Printed copy, 1980. (Box 459, Folder 9)
  - "Time, Probability and Determinism," Speech, Oxford University, Oxford, England, 1967 October 20.
    - Correspondence with J. Ravest, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Notes (Folder 6)
    - Typescript (Folder 7-9)
  - "Erkenntnistheorie und Wissenschaftstheorie," Notes, 1968? (Folder 10)
  - "Problems and History Problem-Situations," Typescript., 1968? (Folder 11)
    Includes letter from L. Landgrebe
  - "The Distributivity of Lattices with Unique Complements,", 1968
    - General (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence.
      Includes copies of text
      - Unidentified, 1968 (Folder 2)
      - Bernays, Paul, 1968 (Folder 3)
      - Bunge, Mario and Marta, 1968 (Folder 4)
      - Dilworth, R. P., 1968 (Folder 5)
      - Hermes, Hans, 1968 (Folder 6)
      - Kleene, Stephen C., 1968 (Folder 7)
      - MacLane, Professor, 1968 (Folder 8)
      - Maddox, John, 1968 (Folder 9)
      - Robinson, Abraham, 1968 (Folder 10)
    - Typescript and holograph (Folder 11-16)
  - "Mathematics, Observation and Physical Thought," in Imre Lakatos and Alan Musgrave, ed., Problems in the Philosophy of Science, Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 17)
  - "On Rules of Detachment and So-Called Inductive Logic," in Imre Lakatos, ed., The Problem of Inductive Logic: Proceedings of the International Colloquium in the Philosophy of Science, Typescript and printed copy, 1968. (Folder 18)
  - "On So-Called Paradoxes in Physics," in Imre Lakatos, ed., Problems in the Philosophy of Science, Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 19)
  - "Plato," International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968
    - General (Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Folder 21)
    - Holograph (Folder 22)
    - Typescript (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - "Remarks on the Problems of Demarcation and of Rationality," in Imre Lakatos, ed., Problems in the Philosophy of Science, 1968
    - General. (Folder 2)
      Includes memoranda, contributions by others, and William W. Bartley, III, "Theories of Demarcation between Science and Metaphysics"
    - Typescript (Folder 3-4)
  - "Theories, Experience and Probabilistic Intuitions," in Imre Lakatos, ed., The Problem of Inductive Logic: Proceedings of the International Colloquium in the Philosophy of Science, 1968
    - General. Discussion by Yehoshua Bar-Hillel of Rudolf Carnap's paper (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Lakatos, Imre, 1967. (Folder 6)
        Includes Imre Lakatos, "Dr. Lakatos on Professor Mercier"
      - Miller, David W., 1967. (Folder 7)